<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Estrian-Chronicles]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Estrian-Chronicles</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 16:26:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 16:26:10 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Valith]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Nestled in a quiet valley of rolling hills and golden fields, Valith presents the quintessential image of a peaceful farming community. With a population of roughly two hundred souls, Valith draws its livelihood from the cultivation of Sungrain, a golden wheat prized throughout the region for its sweet flavor and high yield. The town brews its famous Golden Draft ale from this wheat, turning what might have been a humble hamlet into a renowned waystop for merchants and travelers.<br>Valith is also a crossroads settlement, making it a constant stir of activity. Caravans hauling everything from rare spices to exotic curiosities pass through en route to Estria’s Crown or Holden’s Keep, a fortress belonging to the local lord who oversees Valith. Despite its small size, the town bursts with life and gossip, thanks in part to the presence of adventurous souls who stop by—some seeking only a night’s rest, others chasing rumors of hidden treasures within the nearby Shadowpass Woods.<br><br>The Golden Sheath Tavern is the heart of local hospitality, famed for its Golden Draft and lively atmosphere. On any given evening, one can find farmers unwinding from their labors, merchants sharing news from distant parts of Estria, and the occasional bard or traveler offering tall tales in exchange for a warm meal.<br>Harlan’s Forge, run by the one-legged dwarf Harlan Ironfoot, stands on the outskirts of Valith. Harlan is a retired adventurer whose stories of traveling from the Scorched Waste to the Sapphire Coast have earned him near-celebrity status among the townsfolk. While he spends most of his time repairing farm equipment, Harlan’s skill extends to crafting sturdy swords and armor, especially if the commission intrigues his sense of nostalgia.<br>A small General Store, operated by a cheerful halfling couple, supplies travelers and locals alike with essentials—from oil and lanterns to rope and flour. Well-meaning and always chatty, the couple prides themselves on knowing all the local rumors, which they happily share with paying customers.<br>In the center of town is the Temple of Lysa, modest in structure, yet essential to Valith’s spiritual and communal life. Dedicated to the Goddess of Harvest, its priests publicly ensure that the land’s fertility remains strong and that local offerings to Lysa continue in earnest. Beneath its unassuming façade, however, a secret Thieves’ Guild has taken root. Sister Evelyn, a seemingly soft-spoken cleric, may know far more about clandestine dealings in Valith than she initially lets on.<br>Finally, the Shadowpass Woods loom at the edge of the town’s fields, a dark, twisted forest full of cautionary tales. Stories speak of cursed beasts and hidden relics from Camden’s lost era tucked among the towering pines and overgrown ruins. Travelers who wander too far into the woods report eerie sightings and vanishings that only fuel rumors of an otherworldly taint in the region.<br><br><br><br>]]></description><link>kingdoms/aldamar/valith.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Kingdoms/Aldamar/Valith.md</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 16:26:02 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>