<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Estrian-Chronicles]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Estrian-Chronicles</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 18:45:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 18:45:10 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[1. The Unlikely Sextet]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>In the world of Estria, Along the Eastern-most continent of  lies the Kingdom of <a data-href="Aldamar" href="kingdoms/aldamar/aldamar.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Aldamar</a>. A relatively powerful kingdom in it's own right supplies and trades with many of the surrounding lands due to it's high density of arable land.<br>Aldamar is also home to many adventurer's who seek riches, glory, and fame by uncovering and restoring the ancient Camden artifacts rumored to scatter the land of Averyn. One major hub that most adventurers visit, and end up frequenting is the town of <a data-href="Valith" href="kingdoms/aldamar/valith.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Valith</a>. Located to the South of Aldamar, and along the border of the Sapphire Coast, this small farming town bustles with travelers, merchants, and people from all walks of life, enjoying the famous Golden Draft at the Golden Sheath tavern.<br>One particularly quiet day, a commotion started in the main street of the town when a band of very peculiar people came running down the street, eventually stopped by the well-known, and respected dwarf blacksmith, <a data-href="Harlan Iornfoot" href="important-npcs/harlan-iornfoot.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Harlan Iornfoot</a>.<br>He took them back to his forge to tell them to try and keep their noses clean. A peculiar group they were indeed. A loxodon, Satyr, Hobgoblin, and some sort of animated skeleton composed most of the group along with a human. Humans are the most common race of people but the others were few and far between. The skeleton was slightly unsettling to most.<br>After a while, this band of misfits (at least in racial composition) found out that the town has been having a number of issues recently. The biggest concern is the rising taxes by <a data-href="Lord Wylan Holden" href="important-npcs/lord-wylan-holden.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Lord Wylan Holden</a> whom oversees <a data-href="Holden's Keep" href="kingdoms/aldamar/holden's-keep.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Holden's Keep</a> to the North of Valith, cut off by the Shadowpass Woods. Another issue was the livestock disappearing around the north of town, found either replaced by a puddle of blood, or an unsalvagable corpse with mysterious footprints leading into the woods. Lastly, less of an issue and more of a strange happening was a hooded man who spends all of his time in the tavern guarding a small chest that he keeps close. It's almost as if he is waiting on someone or something to happen.<br>The group decided to investigate the disappearing livestock which led them into the woods where they entered a cave and found themselves in the lair of Troglodytes who have been stealing and eating the livestock. Pushing through the stench, the group defeated a number of troglodytes before coming across a Giant Lizard that they may use as a mount. That was to be decided later, after they took a small break.]]></description><link>the-chronicles/fateforged/1.-the-unlikely-sextet.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">The Chronicles/Fateforged/1. The Unlikely Sextet.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 18:42:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fateforged Chronicles]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>]]></description><link>the-chronicles/fateforged/fateforged-chronicles.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">The Chronicles/Fateforged/Fateforged Chronicles.md</guid><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 18:44:51 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>