<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Estrian-Chronicles]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Estrian-Chronicles</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 21:00:17 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 21:00:17 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Pantheon]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Religion in Estria provides another layer of depth and communal identity. Though each region may favor one deity over others, most accept a unified pantheon that spans from the simplest farmstead to the highest royal court.<br>Arhel, the Lawgiver (Order) stands for social stability, justice, and the careful weighing of scales. Magistrates and city guards who revere Arhel see themselves as stewards of divine law, defending the innocent and meting out punishment for wrongdoers. Conflict often arises between Arhel’s ironclad strictures and Orathal’s celebration of chaos.<br>Balnis, the Grim Watcher (Grave, Death) keeps the final vigil, guiding souls beyond the mortal veil and safeguarding the world against undead abominations. Somber ceremonies honor the lives of the fallen, whether knights on a battlefield or a villager lost to sickness. Tieflings—often shunned—find acceptance in Balnis’s impartial gaze, as their mortal deeds weigh more than their infernal heritage.<br>Dalurus, the Dawn’s Light (Light) provides hope and renewal at every sunrise. Humans and Tabaxi alike say morning prayers to Dalurus for blessings of warmth, clarity, and the banishment of darkness. His priests sometimes stand as the first line of defense against nocturnal horrors.<br>Ethyri, the Twilight Guardian (Twilight) guides those between day and night, watchers at dusk, and protectors of travelers against hidden threats. Firbolgs, who dwell in woodland twilight, offer Ethyri their quiet supplications. Lantern-light ceremonies at the shifting of day into night signify Ethyri’s blessing.<br>Kharvos, the Warbringer (War) stands for martial prowess, discipline, and the fires of conflict that test one’s mettle. Half-orcs and dwarves often fight under Kharvos’s banner, revering honor gained through trial by combat. Though seen as violent by many, his code also insists on a sense of valor and fairness in the art of war.<br>Lysa, the Harvest Mother (Life, Nature) is universally revered for blessing crops and ensuring prosperity. Her worship is strong in farming communities like Valith, where festivals honor the planting and harvesting cycles. The gentle façade of her temples, however, can mask secretive or even illicit activities, such as the Thieves’ Guild that operates beneath the Temple of Lysa in Valith.<br>Maralon, the All-Seeing Sage (Knowledge, Arcana) presides over hidden lore and ancient arcane secrets. Elves and scholars seek his guidance in uncovering relics of the Camden Empire. Libraries dedicated to Maralon are considered neutral ground, their stacks brimming with knowledge both illuminating and dangerous.<br>Myria, the Peaceweaver (Peace, Life) champions reconciliation and diplomatic resolution, seeking to mend the wounds caused by constant warfare. Ceremonies in her name feature burnt offerings of written grievances, symbolizing the release of old grudges. Myria’s priests often accompany armies not to wage war but to offer healing or broker truces.<br>Nimara, the Storm Queen (Tempest) embodies the fury of storms and the cleansing power of rain. Dragonborn, moved by her raw elemental might, are among her most fervent worshipers. Coastal towns host rituals on sea cliffs, casting offerings to the thunderous winds in hopes of either tempering or unleashing nature’s wrath.<br>Orathal, the Laughing Shadow (Trickery) delights in mischief and blurred lines between truth and illusion. Rogues, bards, and changelings invoke Orathal for cunning schemes and quick escapes. Public festivals of Orathal can be raucous and chaotic, testing the patience of more lawful deities’ devotees.<br>Thurim, the Ironheart (Forge) is patron to smiths, builders, and any who reshape the world with hammer and anvil. Dwarves build vast forges in his name, lighting the darkness of mountain halls with molten metal. Gnomes, too, celebrate Thurim’s emphasis on creativity, fusing mechanical brilliance with devout reverence.<br>.<br><br>While the major deities of Estria are honored across kingdoms, many races also revere ancestral gods, totems, and spiritual figures passed down through oral tradition, elder rituals, or racial memory. These racial patrons coexist with the greater pantheon, offering deeper identity to those who still walk the paths of their origin.<br><br><br>Aerisyl, the Moon-Keeper (Twilight, Arcana) guards elven memory and the soft veil between dreams and time. Elves leave tokens for Aerisyl beneath moonlight—lost rings, forgotten letters, or pressed flowers—believing she returns forgotten truths in dreams. Her priests serve as lorekeepers, chroniclers, and gentle soul-guides for those weighed down by ancient grief.<br>Thalandor, the Whispering Wind (Trickery, Nature) is the patron of elven wanderers, poets, and shapeshifters. Each gust of wind carries one of his riddles, and many elves claim he lives in every breath of curiosity. Bards and scouts alike honor him with feathered charms and impromptu performances in sacred groves.<br>Selunevia, the Pale Flame (Life, Grave) represents both the fire of rebirth and the grace of letting go. Elves light floating candles in her name to guide lost souls across rivers and through shadowed woods. Her worship emphasizes the cycle of death as a beautiful continuation rather than a tragic end.<br><br>Khordram, Father of Flame (Forge, Order) is the dwarven god of creation, whose molten breath kindled the first forge. His name is etched into anvils and whispered during the first strike of any great work. Dwarven strongholds often feature shrines where craftspeople offer their calloused hands in silent devotion.<br>Grendora, the Oathbound Matron (Order, Life) is revered as the keeper of ancestral law and kinbound duty. Her worship is central to dwarven family structure, often invoked during marriages, burials, and oaths of fealty. Her clerics serve as judges, midwives, and keepers of genealogies.<br>Volrik the Ember-Eyed (War, Grave) is a dwarven war-saint who blesses shields and sanctifies vengeance. Blacksmiths whisper his name over weapons forged in grief. Dwarves who lose family in battle sometimes take pilgrimages to mountaintop shrines where Volrik’s torch never goes out.<br><br>Nimbleknot the Curious (Arcana, Trickery) is the gnomish spark-god of invention, mistakes, and marvelous accidents. Gnomes leave offerings of failed experiments on makeshift altars, trusting that Nimbleknot will bless them with the next breakthrough—or at least an entertaining explosion.<br>Quenselma, Keeper of Tangents (Knowledge, Mind) is the muse of wandering thoughts, multi-step logic, and brilliant confusion. Gnome scholars keep a “scroll of distractions” beside their main projects, believing each tangent is a sacred whisper from Quenselma. Her temples resemble cluttered libraries filled with clocks, mirrors, and mismatched doors.<br><br>Mella the Breadmother (Life, Peace) presides over halfling hearths and village gardens. Her warmth is felt in shared meals, kind laughter, and the rhythm of small joys. She is rarely worshiped in formal temples—instead, every halfling kitchen becomes a sacred space during the baking of the morning bread.<br>Dobbik of the Dancing Field (Trickery, Nature) is a halfling spirit of luck, laughter, and unexpected joy. Trickster and guardian in one, Dobbik is invoked during playful games, fertility dances, and even drunken bets. His clerics, known as “Laughbound,” travel village to village spreading revelry and riddles.<br><br>Taz'Vokuun, the Binding Flame (Order, War) is the ancient patron of Draconic discipline and strength of will. Depicted as a coiled wyrm encircling a blade, Taz’Vokuun teaches restraint as the highest form of strength. His temples are silent, fire-lit halls where honor is forged and oaths are spoken in flame.<br>Raeth'Issa, the Storm-Eye Matron (Tempest, Arcana) speaks in thunder and watches through lightning. Stormcallers and skyriders seek her guidance before ritual duels and long voyages. Her shrines often take the form of mountaintop monoliths crackling with latent energy.<br><br>Jazhir the Lurking Pounce (Trickery, Nature) is the Tabaxi patron of hunters, stalkers, and ambushers. Depicted as a shadow with golden eyes, Jazhir teaches patience above all. Tabaxi whisper his name before taking the first step of a pursuit. Temples are rare; worship is found in the act itself—the perfect strike.<br>Siviri of Many Songs (Knowledge, Travel) is the keeper of Tabaxi memory and motion. Tales told at sunset become sacred hymns when spoken in her name. Her followers travel the land, leaving trails of stories carved into bark, sewn into fabric, or danced into dust.<br><br>Orelan, the Stillroot (Nature, Life) is the firbolg deity of patience, forest cycles, and communal wisdom. Firbolgs revere Orelan in every act of stewardship, from planting trees to tending elders. Worship involves no temples—just the hush of wind through leaves and the turning of seasons.<br>Velluna, the Veiled Step (Twilight, Grave) guides firbolgs through the thresholds of life and death. Her name is spoken softly at dusk, and her symbol—a crescent moon veiled in pine smoke—is burned onto bark or worn as amulets during funerals and midwinter rites.<br><br>Kael’thir, the Ember Oath (War, Grave) is the fractured patron of Tieflings, known for blazing against injustice. Though estranged from the heavens, Kael’thir is revered for defying both infernal fate and divine rejection. Tieflings mark their bodies with his sigil—an eternal flame—and carve their own legacies in his image.<br>Vel’araxa, the Whispering Nail (Trickery, Knowledge) is the quiet goddess of secrets, scars, and whispered vengeance. Her temples lie in shadowed corners and hidden sanctuaries. Her worshippers leave tokens—a coin pierced, a lock of hair, a sealed confession—offered in the name of wounds too deep to speak aloud.]]></description><link>important-lore/pantheon.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Important Lore/Pantheon.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 20:59:58 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>